Guide to the Frederic Ewen Audiotape and Videotape Collection OH.052
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Public Lectures and Performances (Audiotapes).
  - Master Institute Drama Tours: scene from Aeschylus' Agamemnon - Tape 1 of 2, and scene from Aristophanes' Lysistrata with lecture by Ewen (Performers in the series included Jacob Ben-Ami, Herschel Bernardi, Morris Carnovsky, Howard Da Silva, Ossie Davis, Ruby Dee and John Randolph) (90 minute tape), Jan 31, 1955, Feb 7, 1955 (Box 4, Folder OH 52-37)
  - Master Institute Drama Tours: scene from Aeschylus' Agamemnon- Tape 2 of 2, and Ewen lecture "Elektra" (Performers in the series included Jacob Ben-Ami, Herschel Bernardi, Morris Carnovsky, Howard Da Silva, Ossie Davis, Ruby Dee and John Randolph) (90 minute tape), Jan 31, 1955, Feb 7, 1955 (Box 4, Folder OH 52-38)
  - Master Institute Drama Tours: scene from Sophocles' Oedipus Rex with lecture by Ewen, and Machiavelli's Mandragola(approximately 60 minutes) (Performers in the series included Jacob Ben-Ami, Herschel Bernardi, Morris Carnovsky, Howard Da Silva, Ossie Davis, Ruby Dee and John Randolph) (90 minute tape), Jan 31, 1955, Feb 14, 1955 (Box 4, Folder OH 52-39)
  - Master Institute Drama Tours: scenes from [Sophocles'?] Elektra and Shakespeare's Measure for Measure(Performers in the series included Jacob Ben-Ami, Herschel Bernardi, Morris Carnovsky, Howard Da Silva, Ossie Davis, Ruby Dee and John Randolph) (90 minute tape), Feb 7, 1955, Feb 21, 1955 (Box 4, Folder OH 52-40)
  - Master Institute Drama Tours: scenes from Christopher Marlowe's Dr. Faustus(with Ossie Davis) and Shakespeare's King Henry VI, Part 3 and Measure for Measure(Performers in the series included Jacob Ben-Ami, Herschel Bernardi, Morris Carnovsky, Howard Da Silva, Ossie Davis, Ruby Dee and John Randolph) (90 minute tape), Feb 14, 1955, Feb 21, 1955 (Box 4, Folder OH 52-41)
  - Master Institute Drama Tours: Ewen lecture "Dr. Faustus"; performance of Bertolt Brecht's Mahagonny- Tape 3 of 3 [Tapes 1 and 2 of 3 are on OH 52-54 and OH 52-55] (Performers in the series included Jacob Ben-Ami, Herschel Bernardi, Morris Carnovsky, Howard Da Silva, Ossie Davis, Ruby Dee and John Randolph); performance of Bertolt Brecht's Mother Courage with Germaine Montero and music by Paul Dessau (90 minute tape), Feb 14, 1955, undated (Box 4, Folder OH 52-42)
  - Master Institute Drama Tours: Shakespeare's Measure for Measure and John Webster's Duchess of Malfi(Performers in the series included Jacob Ben-Ami, Herschel Bernardi, Morris Carnovsky, Howard Da Silva, Ossie Davis, Ruby Dee and John Randolph) (90 minute tape), Feb 21, 1955, Feb 28, 1955 (Box 4, Folder OH 52-43)
  - Master Institute Lecture Series on Greek Tragedy and the Modern Playwright: Ewen lecture "Prometheus and Antigone from Goethe and Shelley to Anouilh" - Tape 1 of 2 [duplicates part of OH 52-53] (90 minute tape), Mar 1, 1958 (Box 4, Folder OH 52-44)
  - Master Institute Lecture Series on Greek Tragedy and the Modern Playwright: Ewen lecture "Prometheus and Antigone from Goethe and Shelley to Anouilh" - Tape 2 of 2"Tribute to Robert Burns, in Commemoration of the 200th Anniversary of the Poet's Birth," planned by Ewen with Phoebe Brand, John McLiam, Mary Rose McMaster, Fredi Dundee, Marvin Worden and David Labovitz - Tape 1 of 2 (90 minute tape), Mar 1, 1958, Dec 27, 1959 (Box 4, Folder OH 52-45)
  - Tribute to Robert Burns, in Commemoration of the 200th Anniversary of the Poet's Birth, planned by Ewen with Phoebe Brand, John McLiam, Mary Rose McMaster, Fredi Dundee, Marvin Worden and David Labovitz - Tape 2 of 2. Recordings of works by composer Hanns Eisler: settings of five songs by Bertolt Brecht (Part 1), Nonette #2 and Opus 5(Part 2, continued on OH 52-49) - Tape 1 of 2 (90 minute tape) 2 copies, Dec 27, 1959, undated (Box 4, Folder OH 52-46)
  - Master Institute Lecture Series: Ewen lecture "The Jew in Modern Drama" with readings by Ludwig Donath and John Randolph (approximately 70 minutes) (90 minute tape), Nov 13, 1960 (Box 4, Folder OH 52-47)
  - Camera 3 Production: "Unknown Chekhov" with Ewen and John Randolph; excerpts from Ernst Bloch's Schelomo for cello and Beethoven's Fidelio Overture with a reading by John Randolph (90 minute tape), Dec 24, 1967, undated (Box 4, Folder OH 52-48)
  - Recordings of works by composer Hanns Eisler: Opus 5(Part 2, continued from OH 52-46), settings of songs by Bertolt Brecht (Parts 3 and 4) Riverside Radio Roundtable Series: "Bertolt Brecht in Our Time: Man or Myth?" hosted by Cyril Peters, with Frederick Ewen and Andzej Wirth - Tape 1 of 2 (90 minute tape) 2 copies, undated, Jan 26, 1968 (Box 4, Folder OH 52-49)
  - Riverside Radio Roundtable Series: "Bertolt Brecht in Our Time: Man or Myth?" hosted by Cyril Peters, with Frederick Ewen and Andzej Wirth - Tape 2 of 2 Performance of Bertolt Brecht's Mahagonny- Tape 1 of 3 (60 minutes) [duplicates part of OH 52-54] (90 minute tape), Jan 26, 1968, undated (Box 4, Folder OH 52-50)
  - Ewen lecture on Bertolt Brecht at Columbia University, with John Randolph reading - Tape 1 of 2 (90 minute tape), Mar 18, 1968 (Box 4, Folder OH 52-51)
  - Ewen lecture on Bertolt Brecht at Columbia University, with John Randolph reading - Tape 2 of 2 (approximately 40 minutes)(90 minute tape), Mar 18, 1968 (Box 4, Folder OH 52-52)
  - Recordings of songs and texts by Bertolt Brecht, introduced by Lee Baxandall. Master Institute Lecture Series on Greek Tragedy and the Modern Playwright: Ewen lecture "Prometheus and Antigone from Goethe and Shelley to Anouilh" - Tape 1 of 2 [duplicates part of OH 52-44] (90 minute tape), undated, Mar. 1, 1958 (Box 4, Folder OH 52-53)
  - Performance of Bertolt Brecht's Mahagonny- Tape 1 of 3 (approximately 60 minutes) (90 minute tape), undated (Box 4, Folder OH 52-54)
  - Performance of Bertolt Brecht's Mahagonny- Tape 2 of 3 (approximately 35 minutes) [Tape 3 of 3 is on OH 52-42] (90 minute tape), undated (Box 4, Folder OH 52-55)
  - Performance of Bertolt Brecht's Schweyk in the Second World War with Pia Colombo, Jean Bouise and Clotilde Joans (approximately 60 minutes) (90 minute tape), undated (Box 4, Folder OH 52-56)
- Series III: Readings by Frederic Ewen (Audiotapes).
  - Allingham, William and Lady Emily Tennyson: William Allingham's Diary and Lady Tennyson's Journal (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-59)
  - Annenkov, [Juri Lazarevich?] (90 minute tape) Damaged, undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-60)
  - Arnold, Matthew: from Park Honan's Matthew Arnold: A Life- Tape 1 of 3 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-61)
  - Arnold, Matthew: from Park Honan's Matthew Arnold: A Life- Tape 2 of 3 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-62)
  - Arnold, Matthew: from Park Honan's Matthew Arnold: A Life- Tape 3 of 3 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-63)
  - Arnold, Matthew: Poetry (90 minute tape), Jul 1, 1986 (Box 5, Folder OH 52-64)
  - Balzac, Honoré de: Correspondence (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-65)
  - Borne, Karl Ludwig: Letters From Paris (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-66)
  - Brecht, Bertolt: from Walter Jens' " Poesie und Doktrin: Bertolt Brecht" in Statt einer Literaturgeschichte(approximately 30 minutes); [other unidentified excerpts] (90 minute tape) Side B is blank., Apr 1, 1963 (Box 5, Folder OH 52-67)
  - Browning, Robert - Tape 1 of 2 (90 minute tape) Damaged, undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-68)
  - Browning, Robert and Charles Darwin: from Charles Darwin's Autobiography- Tape 2 of 2 (90 minute tape) Damaged, undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-69)
  - Browning, Robert: from John Maynard's Browning's Youth- Parts 1 and 2 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-70)
  - Browning, Robert: from John Maynard's Browning's Youth- Parts 3 and 4 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-71)
  - Browning, Robert: from Donald Thomas's Robert Browning: A Life Within Life- Tape 1 of 2 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-72)
  - Browning, Robert: from Donald Thomas's Robert Browning: A Life Within Life- Tape 2 of 2 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-73)
  - Carlyle, Thomas: from George Bernhard Tennyson's Sartor Called Resartus: The Genesis, Structure and Style of Thomas Carlyle's First Major Work (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-74)
  - Left-Wing Theater: from Morgan Himelstein's Drama Was a Weapon: The Left-Wing Theatre in New York, 1929-1941(approximately 50 minutes) Cervantes, Miguel de; from Dominic Bevan Wyndham Lewis' The Shadow of Cervantes(approximately 40 minutes) - Tape 1 of 2 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-75)
  - Cervantes, Miguel de; from Dominic Bevan Wyndham Lewis' The Shadow of Cervantes -Tape 2 of 2; excerpts from Friedrich Hölderlin's letters - Tape 1 of 2 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-76)
  - Hölderlin, Friedrich; from Friedrich Hölderlin's letters - Tape 2 of 2 (approximately 10 minutes); chapter on August Strindberg in Maurice Valency's The Flower and the Castle: An Introduction to Modern Drama(approximately 60 minutes); Ramón Menéndez-Pidal's essay "The Genesis of Don Quixote" in Cervantes across the Centuries, ed. Angel Flores and Màir José Bernardete - Tape 1 of 2 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-77)
  - Cervantes, Miguel de; from Ramón Menéndez-Pidal's essay "The Genesis of Don Quixote" in Cervantes across the Centuries, ed. Angel Flores and Màir José Bernardete - Tape 2 of 2 (approximately 15 minutes); commentary by Ewen on journal Jewish Currents(approximately 10 minutes); excerpts from George Gibian's Interval of Freedom: Soviet Literature during the Thaw, 1954-57(approximately 30 minutes) (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-78)
  - Chekhov, Anton: Ward No. 6- Tape 1 of 2 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-79)
  - Chekhov, Anton: Ward No. 6 - Tape 2 of 2 (begins on Side A, continues after interruption on Side B); excerpts from Eric Bentley's The Life of the Drama; excerpts from Carl Viëtor's Die Briefe der Diotima[ an Friedrich Hölderlin] - Tape 1 of 2 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-80)
  - Hölderlin, Friedrich: from Carl Viëtor's Die Briefe der Diotima[ an Friedrich Hölderlin] - Tape 2 of 2 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-81)
  - Chopin, Frederic: Selected Correspondence of Frederic Chopin(90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-82)
  - Clough, Arthur Hugh: from Evelyn Barish Greenberger's Arthur Hugh Clough: The Growth of a Poet's Mind (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-83)
  - Clough, Arthur Hugh: Poetry (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-84)
  - Dante Alighieri: Inferno I-VIII (Tape 1 of 3) (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-85)
  - Dante Alighieri: Inferno VIII, IX, X (Tape 2 of 3) (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-86)
  - Dante Alighieri: Inferno XIII-XV (Tape 3 of 3) (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-87)
  - Darwin, Charles: from Ronald W. Clark's The Survival of Charles Darwin: A Biography of a Man- Tape 1 of 2 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-88)
  - Darwin, Charles: from Ronald W. Clark's The Survival of Charles Darwin: A Biography of a Man - Tape 2 of 2 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-89)
  - Darwin, Charles: from Loren Eiseley's Darwin's Century (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-90)
  - Darwin, Charles: from Howard Gruber's Darwin on Man(90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-91)
  - Darwin, Charles: from Francis Darwin's The Life and Letters of Charles Darwin(120 minute tape) Damaged, undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-92)
  - Dickens, Charles: from Edward Johnson's Charles Dickens: An Introduction to His Novels (90 minute tape) Damaged, undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-93)
  - Dickens, Charles: Letters and Speeches of Dickens vol. 1 (90 minute tape) Damaged, undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-94)
  - Dickens, Charles: Letters and Speeches of Dickens vol. 2 (90 minute tape) Damaged, undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-95)
  - Dickens, Charles: Letters and Speeches of Dickens vol. 3 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-96)
  - Dickens, Charles: from Norman and Jeanne MacKenzie's Dickens: A Life (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-97)
  - Dostoevsky, Fyodor: from Constantin Mochulsky's Dostoevsky: His Life and Work- Tape 1 of 2 (90 minute tape) [Note: the Dostoevsky reading does not begin until after the first minute of tape.], undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-98)
  - Dostoevsky, Fyodor: Constantin Mochulsky's Dostoevsky: His Life and Work- Tape 2 of 2 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-99)
  - Dostoevsky, Fyodor: The Christmas Tree and the Wedding (90 minute tape), undated (Box 5, Folder OH 52-100)
  - Dostoevsky, Fyodor: House of the Dead, chapters V-VII - Tape 1 of 3 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-101)
  - Dostoevsky, Fyodor: House of the Dead, chapter VII - Tape 2 of 3 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-102)
  - Dostoevsky, Fyodor: House of the Dead, chapters 7-9 - Tape 3 of 3 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-103)
  - Dostoevsky, Fyodor: from Joseph Frank's Dostoevsky: The Years of Ordeal, 1850-1859- Tape 1 of 2 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-104)
  - Dostoevsky, Fyodor: from Joseph Frank's Dostoevsky: The Years of Ordeal, 1850-1859- Tape 2 of 2 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-105)
  - Dostoevsky, Fyodor: Letters of Fyodor Dostoevsky to His Family and Friends (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-106)
  - Droz, Jean Pierre - Tape 1 of 2 (missing), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-107)
  - Droz, Jean Pierre - Tape 2 of 2 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-108)
  - Eliot, George: from Gordon Haight's George Eliot and John Chapman, with Chapman's Diaries (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-109)
  - Eliot, George: Letters- Tape 1 of 2 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-110)
  - Eliot, George: Letters- Tape 2 of 2 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-111)
  - Freud, Sigmund: from Louis Fraiberg's Psychoanalysis and American Literary Criticism(45 minute tape), undated [post-1960] (Box 6, Folder OH 52-112)
  - Gaskell, Elizabeth: Ruth and Honoré de Balzac's Correspondence - Part 1 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-113)
  - Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von: Georg Morris Cohen Brandes's Wolfgang Goethe- Tape 1 of 2 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-114)
  - Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von: Georg Morris Cohen Brandes's Wolfgang Goethe- Tape 2 of 2 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-115)
  - Goncharov, Ivan: Oblomov- Tape 1 of 10 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-116)
  - Goncharov, Ivan: Oblomov and Marshal Shatz's Soviet Dissent in Historical Perspective- Tape 2 of 10 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-117)
  - Goncharov, Ivan: Oblomov- Tape 3 of 10 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-118)
  - Goncharov, Ivan: Oblomov- Tape 4 of 10 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-119)
  - Goncharov, Ivan: Oblomov- Tape 5 of 10 (60 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-120)
  - Goncharov, Ivan: Oblomov- Tape 6 of 10 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-121)
  - Goncharov, Ivan: Oblomov- Tape 7 of 10 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-122)
  - Goncharov, Ivan: Oblomov- Tape 8 of 10 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-123)
  - Goncharov, Ivan: Oblomov- Tape 9 of 10 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-124)
  - Goncharov, Ivan: Oblomov- Tape 10 of 10 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-125)
  - Greek Tragedy: Aeschylus and Troy (60 minute tape) Damaged, undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-126)
  - Hölderlin, Friedrich: poetic excerpts; excerpts from Walter Betzendörfer's Hölderlin, neuaufgefundene Jugendarbeiten; excerpts from Dr. Erich Hock's "Dort drüben, in Westphalen": Hölderlins Reise nach Bad Driburg; excerpts from Walter Kirchner's Der Hochverratsprozess gegen Sinclair; [unidentified excerpts] (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-127)
  - Pirandello: Nell'albergo è morto un tale(90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-128)
  - Molière: Ewen's summary of The Misanthrope; excerpts from [Geoffrey Brereton's Jean Racine: A Critical Biography?] - Tape 1 of 2 (90 minute tape) Damaged, undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-129)
  - Molière: The Misanthrope- Tape 2 of 2 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-130)
  - Ruskin, John: from John Dixon Hunt's The Wider Sea: The Life of John Ruskin Tape 1 of 2 (90 minute tape) Damaged, undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-131)
  - Ruskin, John: from John Dixon Hunt's The Wider Sea: The Life of John Ruskin Tape 2 of 2 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-132)
  - Ruskin, John: Letters from Venice and Correspondence with Trevelyan(90 minute tape), Aug 3, 1980 (Box 6, Folder OH 52-133)
  - Russian Literature: Alexsandr Pushkin, Boris Pilnyak and Konstantin Panstovsky (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-134)
  - Russian Literature: Aleksei Tolstoy's Masha(90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-135)
  - Shakespeare, William: Hamlet (2), Troilus and Cressida, Henry VIII, King John, Richard II, Richard III(90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-136)
  - Shakespeare, William: Henry V, Henry VI, Richard III, Two Gentlemen of Verona, Love's Labors Lost, As You Like It, All's Well that Ends Well, Twelfth Night, The Winter's Tale(90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-137)
  - Shakespeare, William: Othello, King Lear, Macbeth, Timon of Athens, Coriolanus, Julius Caesar(60 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-138)
  - Shakespeare, William: Romeo and Juliet, Hamlet, Othello(60 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-139)
  - Shakespeare, William: Sonnets 1-47 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-140)
  - Shakespeare, William: Sonnets 48-92 (60 minute tape) Damaged, undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-141)
  - Shakespeare, William: Sonnets 93-140 (60 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-142)
  - Shakespeare, William: Sonnets 141-154 and Antony and Cleopatra(90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-143)
  - Shakespeare, William: from Ashley Thorndike's Shakespeare's Theater(90 minute tape), undated (Box 6, Folder OH 52-144)
  - Spanish Theater: Ewen commentary on Tirso de Molina (a.k.a. Gabriel Téllez) (approximately 10 minutes); excerpts from Geoffrey Brereton's Jean Racine: A Critical Biography(90 minute tape) Side B is blank., undated (Box 7, Folder OH 52-145)
  - Tennyson, Alfred: Letters, Vol. I (90 minute tape), undated (Box 7, Folder OH 52-146)
  - Tennyson, Alfred: from Robert Bernard Martin's Tennyson: The Unquiet Heart- Parts 1 and 2 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 7, Folder OH 52-147)
  - Tennyson, Alfred: from Robert Bernard Martin's Tennyson: The Unquiet Heart- Parts 3 and 4 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 7, Folder OH 52-148)
  - Tennyson, Alfred: from Robert Bernard Martin's Tennyson: The Unquiet Heart- Parts 5 and 6 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 7, Folder OH 52-149)
  - Tennyson, Alfred: from Hallam Tennyson's Alfred Lord Tennyson: A Memoir by His Son(90 minute tape), undated (Box 7, Folder OH 52-150)
  - Gay, John: excerpts from [an unidentified] book on The Beggar's Opera; recording of reading by [unidentified author] of text critical of American policy in Southeast Asia; excerpts from Louis Fraiberg's Psychoanalysis and American Literary Criticism- Tape 1 of 2 (continued on OH 52-153); recording of performance of a play [by Erwin Piscator?] - Tape 1 of 2 (continued on OH 52-153) (90 minute tape), undated (Box 7, Folder OH 52-151)
  - Piscator, Erwin: from chapter "The Theater of the German Revolution and Piscator" in Jürgen Rühle's Das gefesselte Theater: Vom Revolutionstheater zum sozialistischen Realismus; excerpts from a critical review of Robert Brustein's [ Critical Moments: Reflections on Theater and Society?]; excerpts from Robert Brustein's [ Critical Moments: Reflections on Theater and Society?] (90 minute tape), undated (Box 7, Folder OH 52-152)
  - Piscator, Erwin[?]: recording of performance of a play [by Erwin Piscator?] - Tape 1 of 2 (continued from OH 52-151); reading from [an unidentified French text]; Ewen summary of Leslie Hotson's The First Night of Twelfth Night; excerpts from Louis Fraiberg's Psychoanalysis and American Literary Criticism- Tape 2 of 2 (continued from OH 52-151) (90 minute tape), undated (Box 7, Folder OH 52-153)
  - Turgenev, Ivan Sergeevich: Letters, Vols. 1 and 2 - Tape 1 of 3 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 7, Folder OH 52-154)
  - Turgenev, Ivan Sergeevich: Letters, Vols. 1 and 2 - Tape 2 of 3 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 7, Folder OH 52-155)
  - Turgenev, Ivan Sergeevich: Letters, Vols. 1 and 2 - Tape 3 of 3 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 7, Folder OH 52-156)
  - Turgenev, Ivan Sergeevich: from Patrick Waddington's Turgenev and England (90 minute tape), undated (Box 7, Folder OH 52-157)
  - von Berlichingen, Goetz: Synopsis (90 minute tape) Damaged, undated (Box 7, Folder OH 52-158)
  - Wilde, Oscar: The Nihilists- 1 of 2 (90 minute tape) Damaged, undated (Box 7, Folder OH 52-159)
  - Wilde, Oscar: The Nihilists- 2 of 2 (90 minute tape) Damaged, undated (Box 7, Folder OH 52-160)
- Part 2: Duplicates and Archival Masters. Series I: Audiocassette Tapes. [For Staff Use]
  - Duplicate of OH-52-13 (90 minute tape), May 23, 1990 (Box 8, Folder OH 52-161)
  - Duplicate of OH-52-44 and OH-52-46 (90 minute tape), Mar 1, 1958, Dec 27, 1959 (Box 8, Folder OH 52-162)
  - Duplicate of OH-52-46 (90 minute tape), Dec 27, 1959 (Box 8, Folder OH 52-163)
  - Duplicate of OH-52-47 (90 minute tape) 2 copies, Nov 13, 1960 (Box 8, Folder OH 52-164)
  - Duplicate of OH-52-47 and OH-52-53 (90 minute tape), Nov 13, 1960, undated (Box 8, Folder OH 52-165)
  - Duplicate of OH-52-48 (90 minute tape), Dec 24, 1967 (Box 8, Folder OH 52-166)
  - Duplicate of OH-52-49 and OH-52-54 (90 minute tape), Jan 26, 1968, undated (Box 8, Folder OH 52-167)
  - Duplicate of OH-52-51 and OH-52-52 (90 minute tape) 2 copies, Mar 18, 1968 (Box 8, Folder OH 52-168)
  - Duplicate of OH-52-53 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 8, Folder OH 52-169)
  - Duplicate of OH-52-54, OH-52-55, OH-52-42 and OH-52-56 - Tape 1 of 2 (90 minute tape) 2 copies, undated (Box 8, Folder OH 52-170)
  - Duplicate of OH-52-54, OH-52-55, OH-52-42 and OH-52-56 - Tape 2 of 2 (90 minute tape) 2 copies, undated (Box 8, Folder OH 52-171)
  - Duplicate of OH-52-75, OH-52-76, OH-52-77 and OH-52-78 - Tape 1 of 4 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 8, Folder OH 52-172)
  - Duplicate of OH-52-75, OH-52-76, OH-52-77 and OH-52-78 - Tape 2 of 4 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 8, Folder OH 52-173)
  - Duplicate of OH-52-75, OH-52-76, OH-52-77 and OH-52-78 - Tape 3 of 4 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 8, Folder OH 52-174)
  - Duplicate of OH-52-75, OH-52-76, OH-52-77 and OH-52-78 - Tape 4 of 4 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 8, Folder OH 52-175)
  - Duplicate of OH-52-79, OH-52-80 and OH-52-81 Tape 1 of 3 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 8, Folder OH 52-176)
  - Duplicate of OH-52-79, OH-52-80 and OH-52-81 Tape 2 of 3 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 8, Folder OH 52-177)
  - Duplicate of OH-52-79, OH-52-80 and OH-52-81 Tape 3 of 3 (90 minute tape), undated (Box 8, Folder OH 52-178A & 178B)
  - Master of OH-52-26.A, OH-52-26.B and OH-52-26.C Tape 1 of 2 (90 minute tape) (Box 8, Folder OH 52-178.A & 178.B)
  - Master of OH-52-26.A, OH-52-26.B and OH-52-26.C Tape 2 of 2 (Side A only of 90 minute tape) (Box 8, Folder OH 52-178C)
  - Duplicate of OH-52-26.A, OH-52-26.B and OH-52-26.C CD 1 of 3 (Box 8, Folder OH 52-178D)
  - Duplicate of OH-52-26.A, OH-52-26.B and OH-52-26.C CD 2 of 3 (Box 8, Folder OH 52-178E)
  - Duplicate of OH-52-26.A, OH-52-26.B and OH-52-26.C CD 3 of 3 (Box 8, Folder OH 52-178F)
- Part 2: Duplicates and Archival Masters. Series II: Reel-to-Reel Tapes. [For Staff Use]